excursiopedia.com 2011-11-02

# Privacy Statement

## Privacy Policy

We highly value your trust in choosing Excursiopedia.com for your experience booking. Therefore, we will duly and diligently safeguard and protect the privacy and confidentiality of your personal details (including your credit card details).

This privacy policy applies to all of our services (whether accessed or made available online or through any other platform or device (hereafter collectively referred to as the "website")).

## Information collection

When you make a booking for an excursion (or any other type of experience), you will be asked to complete online forms providing for: your name, (home or office) address, (business or private) email address, (mobile, home or office) telephone number, credit card details (i.e. credit card type and number, CVC code, expiration date, credit card holder name) and to the extent available, reservation preferences. This information is required to process, book and complete your reservation (including the sending of a confirmation email of the booking to you).

## Disclosure of personal details

For our services, we shall collect for the following purposes the following information:

_Reservation orders:_  For the purposes of completing your booking and save for disclosures required by law, criminal investigations, subpoenas or court orders, we will only disclose your name, contact details to the relevant experience provider with which a booking is made. However, please note that from time to time, we may use third party distributors which provide certain services and functions for and on our behalf. These third party distributors may have access to (part of your) personal information in order to perform their services and functions, but are subject to a confidentiality obligation pursuant to which they cannot use, share or disclose the information for any other purpose.

_Surveys_ : By completing a booking, you agree to receive an invitation email to complete our guest review form which we will promptly send to you after your stay of the hotel, which review can also be completed anonymously. By completing the guest review, you agree that the completed guest review can be uploaded to and used on our website at the relevant experience provider information page and excursion information page and on such other platforms and social media (wholly or partly) owned, controlled, managed or hosted by us or our trusted business partners for the sole purpose of informing (future) customers on the service (level) and quality of the relevant experience provider and excursion or event. We reserve the right to adjust, refuse or remove review forms at our sole discretion. The guest review form should be regarded as a survey and does not include any (further commercial) offers, invitations or incentives whatsoever.

_Newsletters and other information_ : If you wish to subscribe for our newsletter or wish to receive promotional communications or other information from us (in respect of our, our affiliated companies' or business partners' products or services), we offer you the option to "Opt in" for this service. If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and other promotional communications, you can simply click on the unsubscribe link.

_Visitor's registration, logging and use of "cookies" and web beacons_ : For (improvement of) our service and product, we use (temporary and persistent) cookies, authorized third parties cookies, web beacons and/or other technologies to collect non-personally identifiable data (e.g. IP address, browser type and Internet Service Provider (ISP) and (for users of our service through a mobile device) Unique Device Identifier, Operating System and Latitude/Longitude) (the "Non-PII") and to track browsing behavior and for specific or tailor made offers or advertisements and monitor and record the visits and use of our website(s).

In order to understand how people use our website and for marketing analysis and quality improvement purposes, we collect, record, process and use on an anonymous basis various data and information, such as the total amount of transactions, viewed web pages, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp information and details like the number and location of (mouse) clicks on a given page, mouse movements, scrolling activity and the (search) words you use and the text you type while being on and using our website (the "Data").

Furthermore, we will also record and use your Non-PII for behavioral targeting, fraud, misuse and criminal investigation purposes.

Please note that from time to time, we may use third party service providers for marketing analysis and quality improvement purposes (the "Service Providers"). We may also use Service Providers to track detailed visitor activity of our visitors or for specific pages. These Service Providers collect, use, monitor and report on the Data and other any information and statistics they collect and analyze your online activities on our website. The information about your use of our website (including the Data, your Non-PII) may be transmitted to and stored on the servers of the Service Providers. Furthermore, the Service Providers may also transfer the collected information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on the Service Provider's behalf.

When visiting and using our website, we do not share any personal information about our customers with our Service Providers and the Service Providers will not collect any personally identifiable information ("PII"). PII does not include your IP address, browser type, Internet Service Provider , Unique Device Identifier, Operating System and Latitude/Longitude. We may share and disclose your personal details and information to a governmental or investigative authority if required by law (or any regulation having the force of law), legal process, criminal investigation, court order or subpoena.

_About cookies and web beacons_ : Cookies are text files stored at your computer, either temporary or persistent on your hard drive. Cookies are used for authenticating, session tracking (state maintenance) and maintaining specific information about the use and users of our website, such as site preferences or the contents of their electronic shopping carts. Cookie files may also be placed at your computer by our trusted third-party advertising companies for the purposes as set out in this paragraph. The data collected by these cookies are completely anonymous. If you prefer, you can delete all cookies that are already on your computer's hard drive by searching for files with "cookie" in it and delete it and for the future, you can edit your browser options such that (future) cookies are blocked; however, please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of our website. For more information about (the use and decline of) cookies, please visit:[ **www.allaboutcookies.org**](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

Web beacon consists of a small string of software code that represents a graphic image request on a Web page or email. There may or may not be a visible graphic image associated with the web beacon and often the image is designed to blend into the background of a Web page or email. Web beacons can be used for many purposes - including site traffic reporting, unique visitor counts, advertising auditing and reporting, and personalization. Web beacons used by Excursiopedia.com collect only anonymous data.

## Protect and safeguard your online privacy

Please note that, in accordance with European personal data protection laws, strict security procedures are observed within Excursiopedia.com to prevent personal data misuse and unauthorized access.

Excursiopedia.com uses trusted and recognized advertising online marketing and analytics companies committed to building consumer awareness and establishing responsible business and data management practices and standards. Most of these companies are a member of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"). The NAI members participate fully in the NAI Principles and offer a general opt-out function of the behavioral advertising. Please visit [ **www.networkadvertising.org**](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) to identify the NAI members that have placed an advertising cookie file on your computer. To opt out of an NAI member's behavioral advertising program, simply check the box that corresponds to the company from which you wish to opt out.

Please note that opting out of a network does not mean you will no longer receive or be subject to online advertising or marketing analysis. It does mean that the network from which you opted out will no longer deliver ads tailored to your web preferences and usage patterns.

## Protect and secure your credit card information

In order to protect and safeguard the personal data provided to us, we have implemented and use appropriate business systems and procedures. For example, your credit card information is transmitted through a secure server protocol, which encrypts all your personal and credit card details. The encryption method used is the industry standard "Secure Socket Layer" (SSL) technology.

Furthermore, we have implemented and use security procedures and technical and physical restrictions for accessing and using personal information. Only authorized employees are permitted to access personal information for performing their duties in respect of our services.

Our server and network are protected by firewalls against unauthorized access and we have intrusion detection systems that monitor and detect unauthorized (attempts to) access to or misuse of our servers.

We don’t store your credit card details, all payments made by world well known professional payment providers.

## Control over your data

You always have the right to review the personal data you have stored with us. You can request your personal data by emailing us at: **[info@excursiopedia.com](mailto:info@excursiopedia.com)**    
Please state 'request personal data' in the subject line of your email.

If your personal data is incorrect, we will change it upon your request. You can also ask Excursiopedia.com to remove your personal data from its database by sending us an email to the aforementioned email address.

## When does Excursiopedia.com send you emails?

After you have made a booking, you will receive a message with all the information about your booking. Several days later, after we confirm your booking on experience provider, you will receive confirmation message (Voucher). You may take this confirmation to the experience provider as proof of the reservation. Shortly prior to your excursion date we may send you an email which may include information on your excursion destination and may provide certain information and offers (including third party offers to the extent that you have actively opted in for this information) relevant to your booking and destination. Furthermore, after your excursion will finished, we will send you the guest review survey, which we appreciate to be filled in by you. Your completed guest review form may be uploaded onto and used on the relevant experience provider’s information page and excursion information page on our website and on such other platforms and social media (wholly or partly) owned, controlled, managed or hosted by us or our trusted business partners for the sole purpose of informing (future) customers of your opinion of the service (level) and quality of the experience provider and excursion. To the extent that you have "Opted in" you may receive from us and from time to time our newsletter or other information.

## Contact

Excursiopedia operated by Big World GmbH.

Big World GmbH is a private limited liability company, incorporated under the laws of Germany and has its offices at Wotanstr 30, 80639 Munich, Germany.

If you have any suggestions or remarks about this privacy statement, please send an email to:  **[info@excursiopedia.com](mailto:info@excursiopedia.com)**

We are at all times entitled to change the way we collect, transmit and process the personal information and such other information as we may deem necessary. This Privacy Statement may therefore be amended from time to time in order to reflect the latest changes
